## **Victor Mandere Mose**

+254707343204 || vicmose.vm@gmail.com || linkedin.com/in/victor-mose || github.com/vmose

#### SUMMARY

Analytics specialist trained in Management Consulting. 4 years experience with 20+ projects completed of varying degrees of complexity and scope in data-modelling, data-visualisation and machine-learning. Knowledgeable in operational frameworks related to data such as Python, SQL and BigQuery. Certified Mobile Developer and Business Intelligence enthusiast.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming: Python, SQL, Javascript, CSS3, HTML5, GraphQL

Software: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Audit Command Language (ACL), Flask, React.js, BigQuery, Git, Excel

Statistical Packages: SPSS, R

**Dashboards/Visuals:** Microsoft PowerBI, Looker Studio, Tableau, D3.js, Python (Matplotlib, Seaborn), **AI/ML:** Linear & Logistic regression, Decision Trees & Random Forest, SVM, PCA, NLP, Recommender

Systems, K-Means Clustering and K-Nearest Neighbour

Version Control: Proficient in Git & Airflow for efficient code collaboration and management.

Languages: English (Fluent), Kiswahili (Native), French (Conversational)

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# DAVIS & SHIRTLIFF Specialist, Analytics & Data Science

Nairobi, Kenya Nov 2022- Present

- Generated data cleaning and preprocessing scripts using Pandas and NumPy, reducing data cleaning time by 70%.
- Built and maintained 150+ interactive data visualisations and business intelligence dashboards using Tableau, Looker, D3.js, Plotly and PowerBI, providing real-time insights to stakeholders and executives.
- Utilized SQL and Python to manipulate complex datasets, resulting in up to 50% reduction in data processing time and ensuring accurate information on project performance, financial performance, human resource performance, and audit and evaluation performance.
- Developed and sustained automated data-processing pipelines using Bash shell scripts, reducing processing time by 50%.
- Constructed and implemented custom machine-learning algorithms using Python and TensorFlow, achieving up to 90% accuracy on classification tasks using cross-validation, grid search, and other techniques to optimise model performance.
- Conducted A/B tests using Google Optimize and Google Analytics to optimise website landing pages achieving an average statistical significance of over 85%, resulting in 20% increase in conversion rates.
- Architected scalable application prototypes using AWS Elastic Beanstalk and EC2, ensuring high availability and fault tolerance with an average iteration time of 1.5 weeks.

### **GRANDE AFRIQUE CONSULTING**

## Data Analytics Consultant

Nairobi, Kenya Nov 2020- Nov 2022

- Applied statistical and predictive modelling techniques to build, maintain, and improve on multiple real-time decision systems with clients reporting a rise in efficiency of up to 40% in day-to-day operations.
- Queried with PostgreSQL, BigQuery, ACL and Arbutus to automate the data flow on routine tasks with each script having over 50 lines on average.
- Coded 100+ programs in Python using established repositories i.e. Pandas, NumPy, scikit-learn
- Visualised over 40 datasets with Python, Microsoft PowerBI and Tableau.
- Led end-to-end delivery of Analytics Support projects for eight quarters, achieving an average client satisfaction rate of over 90%.
- Created complete and effective Project Proposal documents for prospecting stakeholders using the industry standard 6-step process.

### **KENYA FILM COMMISSION**

## Financing and Accounting Intern

Nairobi, Kenya May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Consolidated and migrated 50K+ financial records from disparate systems into Microsoft Navision ERP system; reduced month-end closing time by 40% and strengthened accuracy of financial reports by 50%
- Posted financial transactions into the financial and vote book systems; consolidated over 30 different financial accounts.
- Prepared 20 payment sources documents (vouchers) daily on average while guaranteeing financial credentials were printed in the correct format.
- Contributed to the department's financial forecasting and risk-analysis; findings that brought the commission a boosted budget of 40% from the Ministry of ICT.

#### **EDUCATION**

CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF EAST AFRICA Bachelor of Commerce

Nairobi, Kenya Aug 2016 - Aug 2021

Second Class Honours (Lower)

STRATHMORE SCHOOL

Nairobi, Kenya

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE)

Jan 2012 - Nov 2015

Grade: B+

**CERTIFICATES** 

**Certified Mobile Developer** 

Mar 2016 - Jun 2016

Strathmore University

**DELF A2 Certificate** 

Jan 2014 - Feb 2014

Alliance Françaises

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

### Nyumbani Children's Home

Apr 2013 - Aug 2013

- Streamlined office administration tasks by creating and implementing a digital filing system and automating manual data-entry tasks; reduced administrative errors by 60% and saved the team 30 hours per week
- Managed daily operations over a 7-week period, including meal planning and preparation, inventory management, and cleaning; ensured that all tasks were completed on time and to a high standard